{
  "questions" : [ {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Point out the error in the following program (if it is compiled with Turbo C compiler).",
    "program" : "#include<stdio.h>\nint main()\n{\n    display();\n    return 0;\n}\nvoid display()\n{\n    printf(\"IndiaBIX.com\");\n}",
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "No error", "display() doesn't get invoked", "display() is called before it is defined", "None of these" ],
    "answers" : [ "display() is called before it is defined" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "In this program the compiler will not know that the function display() exists. So, the compiler will generate \"Type mismatch in redeclaration of function display()\". To over come this error, we have to add function prototype of function display(). Another way to overcome this error is to define the function display() before the int main(); function. \n#include<stdio.h>\nvoid display(); /* function prototype */\n\nint main()\n{\n    display();\n    return 0;\n}\nvoid display()\n{\n    printf(\"IndiaBIX.com\");\n}\n Output: IndiaBIX.com Note: This problem will not occur in modern compilers (this problem occurs in TurboC but not in GCC)."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Point out the error in the following program.",
    "program" : "#include<stdio.h>\nint main()\n{\n    void v = 0;\n\n    printf(\"%d\", v);\n\n    return 0;\n}",
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "Error: Declaration syntax error 'v' (or) Size of v is unknown or zero.", "Program terminates abnormally.", "No error.", "None of these." ],
    "answers" : [ "Error: Declaration syntax error 'v' (or) Size of v is unknown or zero." ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Point out the error in the following program.",
    "program" : "#include<stdio.h>\nstruct emp\n{\n    char name[20];\n    int age;\n};\nint main()\n{\n    emp int xx;\n    int a;\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", &a);\n    return 0;\n}",
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "Error: in printf", "Error: in emp int xx;", "No error.", "None of these." ],
    "answers" : [ "Error: in emp int xx;" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "There is an error in the line emp int xx; To overcome this error, remove the int and add the struct at the begining of emp int xx; #include<stdio.h>\nstruct emp\n{\n    char name[20];\n    int age;\n};\nint main()\n{\n    struct emp xx;\n    int a;\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", &a);\n    return 0;\n}"
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Which of the following is correct about err used in the declaration given below?",
    "program" : "typedef enum error { warning, test, exception } err;",
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "It is a typedef for enum error.", "It is a variable of type enum error.", "The statement is erroneous.", "It is a structure." ],
    "answers" : [ "It is a typedef for enum error." ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "A typedef gives a new name to an existing data type. So err is a new name for enum error."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Point out the error in the following program.",
    "program" : "#include<stdio.h>\nint main()\n{\n    int (*p)() = fun;\n    (*p)();\n    return 0;\n}\nint fun()\n{\n    printf(\"IndiaBix.com\\n\");\n    return 0;\n}",
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "Error: in int(*p)() = fun;", "Error: fun() prototype not defined", "No error", "None of these" ],
    "answers" : [ "Error: fun() prototype not defined" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "The compiler will not know that the function int fun() exists. So we have to define the function prototype of int fun(); To overcome this error, see the below program \n#include<stdio.h>\nint fun(); /* function prototype */\n\nint main()\n{\n    int (*p)() = fun;\n    (*p)();\n    return 0;\n}\nint fun()\n{\n    printf(\"IndiaBix.com\\n\");\n    return 0;\n}"
  },
{
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Which of the declaration is correct?",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "int length;", "char int;", "int long;", "float double;" ],
    "answers" : [ "int length;" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "int length; denotes that variable length is int(integer) data type. char int; here int is a keyword cannot be used a variable name. int long; here long is a keyword cannot be used a variable name. float double; here double is a keyword cannot be used a variable name. So, the answer is int length;(Option A)."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Which of the following operations are INCORRECT?",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "int i = 35; i = i%5;", "short int j = 255; j = j;", "long int k = 365L; k = k;", "float a = 3.14; a = a%3;" ],
    "answers" : [ "float a = 3.14; a = a%3;" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "float a = 3.14; a = a%3; gives \"Illegal use of floating point\" error. The modulus (%) operator can only be used on integer types. We have to use fmod() function in math.h for float values."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Which of the following correctly represents a long double constant?",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "6.68", "6.68L", "6.68f", "6.68LF" ],
    "answers" : [ "6.68L" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "6.68 is double. 6.68L is long double constant. 6.68f is float constant. 6.68LF is not allowed in c."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Which of the structure is incorrcet?",
    "program" : "struct aa\n{\n    int a;\n    float b;\n};",
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "1", "2", "3", "1, 2, 3" ],
    "answers" : [ "2" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "Option B gives \"Undefined structure in 'aa'\" error."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "Which of the structure is correct?",
    "program" : "struct book\n{\n    char name[10];\n    float price;\n    int pages;\n};",
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "1", "2", "3", "All of above" ],
    "answers" : [ "1" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "In 2 and 3 semicolon are missing in structure element."
  }, {
    "id" : null,
    "category" : null,
    "level" : null,
    "question" : "",
    "program" : null,
    "type" : "radio",
    "showNumAnswers" : false,
    "options" : [ "1 correct", "2 correct", "3 correct", "1, 2, 3 are correct" ],
    "answers" : [ "3 correct" ],
    "selected" : null,
    "answerDescription" : "typedef long a; extern int a c; while compiling this statement becomes extern int long c;. This will result in to \"Declaration syntax error\". typedef long a; extern a int c; while compiling this statement becomes extern long int c;. This will result in to \"Too many types in declaration error\". typedef long a; extern a c; while compiling this statement becomes extern long c;. This is a valid c declaration statement. It says variable c is long data type and defined in some other file or module. So, Option C is the correct answer."
  }  ],
  "currentIndex" : 0,
  "testMillis" : 0,
  "testTime" : false,
  "remainingTimeInitialized" : false,
  "remainingTestMillis" : 0,
  "ref" : "https://www.indiabix.com/c-programming/declarations-and-initializations/003001"
}